<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shared Documentation on Carvel</title>
    <link>/shared/docs/latest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shared Documentation on Carvel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/shared/docs/latest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contributor Covenant Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>/shared/docs/latest/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/shared/docs/latest/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>Our Pledge ¶In the interest of fostering an open and welcoming environment, we as contributors and maintainers pledge to making participation in this project and our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression, level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal appearance, race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.
Our Standards ¶Examples of behavior that contributes to creating a positive environment include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Contribute</title>
      <link>/shared/docs/latest/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/shared/docs/latest/contributing/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;d love to accept your patches and contributions to this project. Please review the following guidelines you&amp;rsquo;ll need to follow in order to make a contribution.
Communication ¶We prefer communicating asynchronously through GitHub issues and the #carvel Slack channel. In order to be inclusive to the community, if a conversation related to an issue happens outside of these channels, we appreciate summarizing the conversation&amp;rsquo;s context and adding it to an issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Policy</title>
      <link>/shared/docs/latest/security-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/shared/docs/latest/security-policy/</guid>
      <description>The VMware Security Response Centre Team provides a single point of contact for the reporting of security vulnerabilities in Carvel (part of VMware) products and coordinates the process of investigating any reported vulnerabilities.
Reporting a Vulnerability ¶We strongly encourage people to report security vulnerabilities privately to our security team before disclosing them in a public forum.
The e-mail address to use to contact the team is security@vmware.com.
Please note that the e-mail address above should only be used for reporting undisclosed security vulnerabilities in Carvel (part of VMware) products and managing the process of fixing such vulnerabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
